Guide to the Winterhouse Art and Design Collection of Volume 1 Number 1
Yale University Arts Library
Winterhouse Art and Design Collection of Volume 1 Number 1
1917-2011
1960-2010
ART 14
Yale University Arts Library
10
(8 boxes)
The collection consists of first issues of journals ranging from small press and literary to popular culture.
Drenttel, William, 1953-2013
Helfand, Jessica, 1960-
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of William Drenttel and Jessica Helfand, 2011, 2012, 2013.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Biographical / Historical
William Drenttel received a B.A. from Princeton University in 1977 with an Independent Concentration in Film and European Cultural Studies. From 1977-1985, Drenttel was a senior vice president at Saatchi & Saatchi. From 1985-1997, Drenttel was the president of Drenttel Doyle Partners. One of the leading design firms in America, the firm won over 300 design awards. Since 1997, William Drenttel worked in partnership with Jessica Helfand at Winterhouse, a design consultancy focusing on editorial development and online media; cultural and educational institutions; and social innovation initiatives. In 2002, Drenttel co-founded Design Observer, a site of design news and cultural criticism; today, the site is a leading design publication with over a million site visits a month.
Drenttel was also co-editor of Below the Fold, a journal of visual culture published by Winterhouse; the founder of the Polling Place Photo Project, an online election documentation project run in collaboration with AIGA and The New York Times; and a Senior Faculty Fellow at the Yale School of Management teaching design and innovation. As a publisher, Drenttel created books under the Winterhouse imprint for Yale University Press, University of Chicago Press and Princeton Architectural Press. He published literary works ( Susan Sontag, Thomas Bernhard, Paul Celan ); bibliographic works (catalogues for the Grolier Club ); public policy (National Security Strategy of the U.S.); history (Kafka and film, and the 1943 destruction of Hamburg); and art and design history ( Siri Hustvedt, Michael Bierut and Jessica Helfand ).
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of 266 first issues of journals ranging from small press and literary to popular culture.
Arrangement
Organized into two series: I. About, 1996-2007. II. Examples, 1919-2011.
Design
- About, 1996-2007; Series I
  Arrangement
  Arranged alphabetically by title.
  - American Periodicals: A Collector's Manual and Reference Guide. First edition. West Orange, New Jersey: Steven Lomazow, 1996. pp. 599. (Box 6, Folder 235)
    Scope and Contents
    Compiled by Steven Lomazow, M.D.
  - Below the Fold. Volume 1: Number 1. Falls Village, Connecticut: Winterhouse Institute, Spring 2006. pp. 16. (Box 7, Folder 270)
    Edited by William Drenttel and Jessica Helfand.
    Article of note: "Volume One, Number One."
    Design by Winterhouse.
  - Idea. Volume 55: Number 322. Tokyo: Seibundo Shinkosha Publishing, May 2007. pp. 196. (Box 6, Folder 236)
    Edited by Toshiaki Koga.
    Article of note: "Journal Culture" by William Drenttel.
    Design by Shirai Design Studio.
- Examples, 1919-2011; Series II
  - 2wice: Visual / Culture / Document. Volume One: Number One. New York: 2wice, 1997. pp. 92. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Edited by J. Abbott Miller.
    Contributions by Georges Bataille, Geoffrey Beene and Rosalind Krauss.
    Article of note: "Feet without Fetish."
    Design by Design Writing Research.
  - 306090: A Journal of Emergent Architecture and Design. Number One. Princeton: Princeton University School of Architecture, September 2001. pp. 96. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Edited by Jennifer Ferng and Jonathan Solomon.
    Contributions by M. Christine Boyer, Kevin Lippert and Philip Nobel.
    Article of note: "Capturing Stillness."
  - 45 grams. Issue One. Chicago: Tanagram Partners, 2006. pp. 10. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Contributions by Yann Legendre and Eric Wagner.
    Design by Tanagram.
  - 48 Hour Magazine. Issue Zero. Palo Alto: MagCloud. May 2010. pp. 60. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Edited by Heather Champ.
    Contributions by Mark McClusky, Andy Price and Marissa Madrigal.
    Article of note: "The Gold Diggers."
  - @Issue: The Journal of Business & Design. Volume 1: Number 1. Boston: Corporate Design Foundation, Fall 1995. pp. 28. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Edited by Delphine Hirasuna.
    Contributions by Dennis DeBiase, Delphine Hirasuma and Shelby Hypes.
    Article of note: "Why Federal Express Became FedEx."
    Design by Kit Hinrichs, Pentagram.
  - Ambidextrous. Issue One. Palo Alto: Stanford University, Summer 2005. pp. 52. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Edited by Wendy Ju and W. Lawrence Neeley.
    Contributions by Michael Helms, Erica Robles and Sean White.
    Article of note: "Functional Manifesto."
  - The American: A Magazine of Ideas. Volume One: Number One. Washington, DC: American Enterprise Institute, November/December 2006. pp. 120. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Edited by James K. Glassman.
    Contributions by Joel Kotkin, Lizbeth Scordo and Alberto Conti.
    Article of note: "The Glorious Art of Business."
    Design by Alexander Isley.
  - American Journal of Bioethics. Volume One: Number One. Cambridge, Massachusetts: MIT Press, Winter 2001. pp. 76. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Edited by Glenn McGee and David Magnus.
    Contributions by Norman Daniels, Judith Dar and Carson Strong.
    Article of note: "Gender by Design: Not Yet Ready for Prime Time."
  - The American Poetry Review. Volume One: Number One. Philadelphia: World Poetry, November–December 1972. pp. 48. (Box 7, Folder 237)
    Edited by Stephen Berg and Stephen Parker.
    Contributions by Richard Howard, Philip Levine, Pablo Neruda, Joyce Carol Oates and Diane Wakoski.
    Article of note: "The Craft of Plumbers, Carpenters, & Mechanics."
    Design by Sam Maitin.
  - Amphibian: A Letterpress Zine. Issue One. Berkeley: One Heart Press, 2004. pp. 20. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    Edited by Leif Fairfield.
    Contributions by Michael Bartalos, Keith Gidlund and J. Chadwick Johnson.
    Article of note: "Lincoln Logs for Hippies."
  - Anathema. Issue One. New York: Anathema, 2005. pp. 64. (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Edited by Ken Miller.
    Contributions by James Fuentes, Andrew Kuo and Noah Sheldon.
    Article of note: "Torture and Memory: The Oubliette as Camera Obscura."
    Design by Dmitri Siegel.
  - Antaeus. Number One. Tangier, Morocco: Antaeus, Summer 1970. pp. 96. (Box 1, Folder 11)
    Edited by Daniel Halpern and Paul Bowles.
    Contributions by John Berryman, Jane Bowles, Lawrence Durrell, John Fowles, Jerzy Kosinski and Tennessee Williams.
    Article of note: "Ezra Pound at St. Elizabeth's."
  - Ante: Journal of the Students of the Yale University School of Art. Volume One: Number One. New Haven: Yale University School of Art, November 2002. pp. 60. (Box 1, Folder 12)
    Edited by Nicholas Herman.
    Contributions by Sean Bluechel, Michael Cloud and Dmitri Siegel.
    Article of note: "Tobias Frere-Jones Spells New York."
  - ANY: Architecture New York. Number Zero. New York: Anyone Corporation, May–June 1993. pp. 62. (Box 7, Folder 238)
    Edited by Cynthia Davidson and Michael Speaks.
    Contributions by Jacques Derrida, Peter Eisenman, John Hejduk, Rem Koolhaas, Michael Sorkin and Bernard Tschumi.
    Article of note: "Probable Geometries: The Architecture of Writing in Bodies."
    Design by Massimo Vignelli.
  - Arachne: An Interdisciplinary Journal of Language and Literature. Number One. Sudbury, Canada: Laurentian University, 1994. pp. 142. (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Edited by David Darby.
    Contributions by Jonathan Hart, Brian Schaffer and Muriel Usandivaras.
    Article of note: "Perspectives on Postcolonial Theories."
  - The Archeworks Papers. Volume One: Number One. Chicago: Archeworks, 2004. pp. 44. (Box 1, Folder 14)
    Edited by Stanley Tigerman.
    Article of note: "Healing the World: A Challenge for Designers."
    Design by Alisa Wolfson.
  - Architecture Plus: The International Journal of Architecture. Volume One: Number One. New York: Informat Publishing, February 1973. pp. 108. (Box 1, Folder 15)
    Edited by Peter Blake.
    Contributions by Henry Liu and Robert Maxwell.
    Article of note: "A Benign Machine for Living."
    Design by Charlotte Winter.
  - Arshile: A Magazine of the Arts. Number One. Los Angeles: 96 Tears Press, Spring 1993. pp. 140. (Box 1, Folder 16)
    Edited by Mark Salerno.
    Contributions by Dore Ashton, Tom Clark and Robert Creeley.
    Article of note: "Some Perplexed Ideas at the End of the Century."
    Design by Ted Williams.
  - Art and Literature: An International Review. Number One. Paris: Société Anonyme d'Editions Littéraires, March 1964. pp. 244. (Box 1, Folder 17)
    Edited by John Ashbery, Anne Dunn, Rodrigo Moynihan and Sonia Orwell.
    Contributions by Gaston Bachelard, Donald Bartheleme, Cyril Connolly, Jean Genet and Adrian Stokes.
    Article of note: "Fifty Years of Little Magazines."
    Typography by Pierre Faucheux.
  - Art Review. Issue 01. London: ArtReview, July 2006. pp. 154. (Box 1, Folder 18)
    Edited by John Weich.
    Contributions by Matthew Herert, Julia Peyton-Jones and Ben Lewis.
    Article of note: "Paris on the Rebound."
    Design by Akihiro Nakayama.
  - Art Xpress. Volume 1: Number 1. Providence, Rhode Island: Art Express Limited, May–June 1981. pp. 96. (Box 1, Folder 19)
    Edited by Kenneth S. Friedman.
    Contributions by Peter Frank, Janet Goleas and Patricia Stewart.
    Article of note: "Postal Modernism: Artists' Stamps and Stamp Images."
    Design by Malcolm Grear.
  - Arts in Virginia. Volume One: Number One. Virginia Museum of Fine Arts, Fall 1960. pp. 32. (Box 1, Folder 20)
    Edited by Fred Frechette.
    Contributions by Paul N. Perrot and Mrs. Richard W. Black.
    Article of note: "A Forgotten American Sculptor."
    Design by Richard DeNatale.
  - Artificial Life. Volume One: Number One. Cambridge, Massachusetts: MIT Press, Fall 1993–Winter 1994. pp. 248., 1993-1994 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    Edited by Christopher Langton.
    Contributions by Kunihiko Kaneko and Luc Steels.
    Article of note: "Evolutionary Approach to Synthetic Biology: Zen and the Art of Creating Life."
  - The Artist's Magazine. Premier Issue. Cincinnati, Ohio: Fletcher Art Services, January 1984. pp. 96. (Box 1, Folder 22)
    Edited by Richard Rosenthal.
    Contributions by Sally Ann Davis, J. Ray Doyle and Fritz Henning.
    Article of note: "Meeting the Challenge of Watercolor."
    Design by Steve Phillips Design.
  - Aspen Magazine. Volume One: Number One. New York: Aspen Magazine, 1965. (Box 7, Folder 239)
    Edited by Phyllis Johnson.
    Contributions by Peggy Clifford, Philip Hauser and Konrad Wachsmann.
    Article of note: "The 15th Annual International Design Conference."
    Design by George Lois, Tom Courtos and Ralph Tuzzo.
  - The Atlantic. (Issue One of 2008 Redesign.) Washington DC: Atlantic Media Company, November 2008. pp. 144. (Box 1, Folder 23)
    Edited by James Bennet.
    Contributions by Michael Bierut, Charles C. Mann and Clay Risen.
    Article of note: "A Question of Balance."
    Design by Michael Bierut, Pentagram.
  - Audience: A Quarterly Review of Literature and the Arts. Volume One: Number One. Cambridge, Massachusetts: Audience Press, May 1957. pp. 64. (Box 1, Folder 24)
    Edited by Peter Michael Wyman.
    Contributions by Donald Hall, John Hollander and I. A. Richards.
    Article of note: "The Western Epic Tradition in the West."
    Cover design by Guy Davenport.
  - Aufgabe. Number One. New York: Litmus Press, Summer 2001. pp. 312. (Box 1, Folder 25)
    Edited by E. Tracy Grinnell.
    Contributions by George Albon, Mary Burger and Elizabeth Treadwell.
    Article of note: "Covers and Title Pages From Some of France's Poetry Publications."
    Design by Guy Bennett.
  - Autodafe: The Journal of the International Parliament of Writers. Number One. New York: Seven Stories Press, Spring 2001. pp. 280. (Box 1, Folder 26)
    Edited by Christian Salmon.
    Contributions by Russell Banks, Jacques Derrida, Margaret Drabble, Salman Rushdie and Wole Soyinka.
    Article of note: "The Sacred River: War in Sierra Leone."
    Design by Paul-Raymond Cohen.
  - Avant Garde. Number 1. New York: Avant-Garde, Inc., January 1968. pp. 60. (Box 7, Folder 240)
    Edited by Ralph Ginzburg.
    Contributions by Warren Boroson, Julio Mitchel and Muhammad Ali.
    Article of note: "What Makes Nixon Run?"
    Design by Herb Lubalin.
  - Baseline. Volume One: Number One. New York: Ziff Davis, October 2001. pp. 104. (Box 1, Folder 27)
    Edited by Tom Steinert-Threlkeld.
    Contributions by Edward Cone, Mary Jo Foley and Tom Steinert-Threlkeld.
    Article of note: "The Ultimate CRM Machine."
    Design by Patti Gareri.
  - Bauble. Number One. Brooklyn: A Black Plum Production. pp. 8., undated (Box 1, Folder 28)
    Edited by Kai Lundgren-Williams.
    Contributions by Trent Williams.
    Article of note: "The Movable Café."
    Design by Black Plum.
  - The Believer. Volume One: Number One. San Francisco: The Believer, March 2003. pp. 128. (Box 1, Folder 29)
    Edited by Heidi Julavits and Ed Park.
    Contributions by Anne Carson, Jonathan Lethem and Jim Shepard.
    Article of note: "Conversation between Salman Rushdie and Terry Gilliam."
  - Brill's Content. Issue One. New York: Brill, August 1998. pp. 152. (Box 1, Folder 30)
    Edited by Steven Brill.
    Contributions by Steven Brill, David McClintick and Roger Parloff.
    Article of note: "Pressgate."
    Design by Caroline Bowyer.
  - Blueprint: Design Your Life. Premier Issue. New York: Martha Stewart Living Omnimedia, Summer 2006. (Box 1, Folder 31)
    Edited by Rebecca Thuss.
    Contributions by Rory Evans, Elizabeth Graves and Kimberly Stevens.
    Article of note: "Charm School: Modernize A Hand-Me-Down Charm Bracelet."
    Design by Eric A. Pike.
  - Canarium. Number One. Ann Arbor, MI: Canarium Books, 2008. pp. 96. (Box 1, Folder 32)
    Edited by Joshua Edwards, Robyn Schiff, Nick Twemlow and Lynn Xu.
    Contributions by Srikanth Reddy, Arda Collins and Cole Swensen.
    Article of note: "Of Brother Making."
    Cover art by Naomi Reis.
  - Cannot Connect. Number One. 2007. pp. 64. (Box 1, Folder 33)
    Edited by Gordon Matta-Clark.
    Contributions by Ned Smyth, Micha F. Lindemans and Lois Cecchini.
    Article of note: "Rock Me, Aphrodite."
  - Canteen: The State of Creation. Issue One. Brooklyn: Canteen Magazine, 2007. pp. 96. (Box 1, Folder 34)
    Edited by Sean Finney.
    Contributions by Katie Ford, Julie Orringer and Dennis Leary.
    Article of note: "Prologomena to a Future Restaurant."
    Design by Sai Sriskandarajah.
  - Carson. Issue 1. Los Angeles: Carson Media, 2011. pp. 86. (Box 1, Folder 35)
    Edited by Alex Storch.
    Contributions by Davide Berruto, Jessica Halem and Charlotte Biddy.
    Article of note: "Save a Life: Know Your Role in a Medical Emergency."
    Design by Spoe-art.
  - Chirimo. A Thrice Yearly Review of Rhodesian and International Poetry. Number 1. Salisbury, Rhodesia: Berry Trust, June 1968. pp. 32. (Box 1, Folder 36)
    Edited by C.T.E. Style and K.O. Style.
    Contributions by Roy Fuller, Allen Ginsberg and Edward Lucie-Smith.
    Cover design by Trevor Percy-Lancaster.
  - Clinical Social Work Journal. Volume 1: Number 1. New York: Behavioral Publications, Spring 1973. pp. 64. (Box 1, Folder 37)
    Edited by Mary L. Gottesfeld.
    Contributions by Margaret Bonnefil, Phyllis Caroff and David Edwards.
    Article of note: "The Repulsive Client.
  - Clio: An Interdisciplinary Journal of Literature, History, and the Philosophy of History. Volume 1: Number 1. Kenosha, Wisconsin: University of Wisconsin, October 1971. pp. 56. (Box 1, Folder 38)
    Edited by Robert Canary and Henry Kozicki.
    Contributions by L. B. Cebik, Thomas Hayes and Robert Spiller.
    Article of note: "The Literary Criticism of History."
  - Coin-Op: The Nest Egg. Number One. Arcata, CA: Coin-Op Studio, 2008. pp. 16. (Box 1, Folder 39)
    Design by Peter and Maria Hoey.
  - Colors. Volume One: Number One. New York: United Colors of Benetton, Fall-Winter 1991. pp. 63. (Box 7, Folder 241)
    Edited by Oliviero Toscani and Tibor Kalman.
    Contributions by Peter Heffernan, Mark Schapiro and Jeff Spurrier.
    Article of note: "Heroes for the Real World."
    Design by M&Co.
  - Colour. Issue 1. London: John Brown Contract Publishing, Spring 2000. pp. 50. (Box 7, Folder 242)
    Edited by Jan Burney.
    Contributions by Jeremy Myerson and Hugh Aldersey-Williams.
    Article of note: "All in the Mind."
    Design by Kristen Willey.
  - The Common. Issue 01. Amherst, MA: Common Foundation, 2011. pp. 149. (Box 1, Folder 40)
    Edited by Jennifer Acker.
    Contributions by Maria Terrone, Sabina Murray and Ted Conover.
    Article of note: "Brown Road."
    Design by Gabriele Wilson Design.
  - Condé Nast Portfolio. Premier Issue. New York: Condé Nast Publications, May 2007. pp. 328. (Box 1, Folder 41)
    Edited by Joanne Lipman.
    Contributions by Tom Wolfe, Daniel Roth and Gabriel Sherman.
    Article of note: "The New Masters of the Universe."
    Design by Robert Priest.
  - Conditions: A Magazine of Writing by Women with An Emphasis On Writing by Lesbians. Volume One: Number One. New York: Conditions, April 1977. pp. 148. (Box 1, Folder 42)
    Edited by Elly Bulkin, Jan Clausen, Irena Klepfisz and Rima Shore.
    Contributions by Maureen Brady, Susan Krieger and Ann Williams.
    Article of note: "Radclyffe Hall and the Lesbian Image."
    Cover art by Irene Pesikis.
  - Connect: Art, Politics, Theory, Practice. Number One. New York: Arts International, Fall 2000. pp. 200. (Box 1, Folder 43)
    Edited by Radhika Subramaniam.
    Contributions by Ann Biersteker, Venus Khoury-Ghata and Karen van Dyck.
    Article of note: "The Asmara Declaration on African Languages and Literatures."
  - Constitution: A Quarterly Journal of the Foundation for the U.S. Constitution. Volume One: Number One. New York: Foundation for the U.S. Constitution, Fall 1988. pp. 64. (Box 1, Folder 44)
    Edited by John A Meyers.
    Contributions by Warren E. Burger, Lynne V. Cheney and William E. Simon.
    Article of note: "The Constitution and Economic Liberty."
    Design by John R. Martinez.
  - The Contemporary. Volume One: Number One. Detroit: Mel Jerome Ravitz, Winter 1946. pp. 44. (Box 1, Folder 45)
    Edited by Mel Jerome Ravitz.
    Contributions by Howard Fast, Bernard Rosenberg and Stephen Spender.
    Article of note: "Man in A Planned Society."
    Design by Cyril Aronson.
  - Continental Drifter. Volume 1: Number 1. Colorado: University of Colorado, 1984. pp. 86. (Box 1, Folder 46)
    Edited by Edward Dorn.
    Contributions by Tom Clark, Robert Creeley and Donald Wesling.
    Article of note: "The Romantic Foundations of Modern Poetics."
    Cover art by Tom Clark.
  - Contours: A Journal of the African Diaspora. Volume One: Number One. Champaign, Illinois: University of Illinois Press, Spring 2003. pp. 128. (Box 1, Folder 47)
    Edited by David Barry Gaspar.
    Contributions by Grant Farred, Michael Honey and Winston Napier.
    Article of note: "Embodied Identities: Sport and Race in South Africa."
  - Convair Transport Service News. Volume One: Number One. San Diego: Convair, April 1957. pp. 12. (Box 1, Folder 48)
    Edited by G. S. Hunter.
    Contributions by Ralph L. Bayless, H.R. Kennedy and N.J. Rutherford.
    Article of note: "Development of the T-29, C-131, and R4Y Models."
    Design by N. J. Rutherford.
  - Conveyer: Articulating and Documenting Jersey City's Sense of Place Through Imagemaking and Storytelling. Issue One. Jersey City, NJ: Conveyer, Summer 2006. pp. 80. (Box 1, Folder 49)
    Edited by Josef Reyes.
    Contributions by Brendan Carroll, Jose Masaoy and Robert Vargas.
    Article of note: "Five Years in Five Months on Fifth Street."
    Design by Josef Reyes.
  - Cookie. Volume One: Issue One. New York: Fairchild, December 2005–January 2006. pp. 276., 2005-2006 (Box 1, Folder 50)
    Edited by Pilar Guzmán.
    Contributions by Lori Leibovich, Manny Howard and Jennifer Tung.
    Article of note: "The First Birthday."
    Design by Kirby Rodriguez.
  - Cooper-Hewitt National Design Museum. Volume One: Number One. New York: Smithsonian Institution, Autumn 1994. pp. 64. (Box 2, Folder 51)
    Edited by Nancy Aarke.
    Article of note: "Redesigning the National Design Museum: A Conversation between National Design Museum Director Dianne Pilgrim and James Stewart Polshek and Partners Architects."
    Design by Drenttel Doyle Partners.
  - The Country Book: A Digest of Country Living from the Country. Volume One: Numbers 1–4. Camden, New Jersey: The Country Book, Summer 1941–Spring 1942. pp. 160., 1941-1942 (Box 2, Folder 52)
    Edited by Erwin D. Swann.
    Contributors include David Graham, Henry Tetlow and Lawrence Simpson.
    Article of note: "You Can't Eat the Natives."
  - Crowd. Volume One: Issue One. New York: Crowd Magazine, Fall/Winter 2001. pp. 127. (Box 2, Folder 53)
    Edited by Aimee Kelley and Lily Saint.
    Contributions by Rafael Campo, Richard Prince and Timothy Westmoreland.
    Article of note: "Paintings from A Collaboration with John Ashbery."
    Design by A.C. Chapman.
  - Cultural Critique. Number One. New York: Society for Cultural Critique, Fall 1985. pp. 216. (Box 2, Folder 54)
    Edited by Donna Przybylowicz.
    Contributions by Jurgen Habermas, Edward W. Said and Cornel West.
    Article of note: "Is the Subject of Science Sexed?"
  - Culture and Travel. Premiere Issue. Volume 1: Issue 1. New York: LTB Media, September/October 2006. pp. 144. (Box 7, Folder 243)
    Edited by Michael Boodro.
    Contributions by Madhur Jaffrey, Lucinda Rogers and Herbert Muschamp.
    Article of note: "Pooris and Picnics."
    Design by Emily Crawford.
  - Curious Rooms: A Literary Journal. Volume One: Number One. New Haven: Curious Rooms, February 1999. pp. 168. (Box 2, Folder 55)
    Edited by Cynthia Cross and Christine Japely.
    Contributions by Edward Sorel, Laurel Speer and Susan Volchok.
    Article of note: "I was a fantastic writer but publishers ignored me!"
    Design by Denise Brady.
  - Cybernetic: The Magazine. Volume One: Number One. Fairfax, Virginia: American Society for Cybernetics, Summer–Fall 1985. pp. 148. (Box 2, Folder 56)
    Edited by Paul Trachtman.
    Contributions by Wendell Berry, Paul Pangaro and Norbett Wiener.
    Article of note: "To Hold Discourse with A Computer."
    Design by Bruce McIntosh.
  - D-Crit Chapbook: At the Water's Edge. Number 1. New York: School of Visual Arts MFA Design Criticism, Spring 2011. pp. 100. (Box 2, Folder 57)
    Edited by Akiko Busch, Saundra Marcel and Vera Sacchetti.
    Contributions by Sarah F. Fox, Aileen Kwun and Vera Sacchetti.
    Article of note: "Some Versions of Pastoral."
    Design by Walker Design.
  - The D-Crit Florilegium. New York: School of Visual Arts, Summer 2010. pp. 12. (Box 7, Folder 244)
    Contributors include Hala Abdulmalak, William Myers and Amelia Black.
    Article of note: "Al-Kafiye: A Potent Symbol Uncovered.
  - DDDDoomed—Or, Collectors & Curators of the Image: A Brief Future History of the Image Aggregator. Volume I of VII in a Series. Minneapolis: Edition MK, 2010. pp. 77. (Box 2, Folder 58)
    Design by R. Gerald Nelson.
  - Delos. Volume One: Number One. College Park, Maryland: Center for World Literature, 1988. pp. 158. (Box 2, Folder 59)
    Edited by Reed Whittemore.
    Contributions by Nancy Esposito, Milne Holton and Howard Norman.
    Article of note: "Twelve Poets of an Illumined Nicaragua."
    Design by Lynn Springer.